Hi everybody, welcome back to the
channel. Today we're going to do
another keto friendly (so no sugar) ice cream
and it's chocolate caramel AKA Rolo ice cream.
So another keto recipe, I did the rebel coffee
chip, amazing ice cream... really really good I
mean uh things have labels for everything these
days, I'm so fed up with labels for everything.
Just make something and enjoy it. That Rebel
coffee chip ice cream was exquisite you know,
regardless of what style recipe, it is excellent
and anyone would love it so we're going to do it
again we're not going to copy anyone we're going
to make our own, my own, so we're going to do a
chocolate ice cream with a caramel swirl and this
is inspired by Rolos because everyone loves rollos
and if you don't why not. In England they were
really hard, the caramel was solid as a rock
over here they're lovely and gooey and squishy so
yeah that's what we're going to do. First thing
we're going to do is get all our ingredients ready
for our ice cream like that and what we have here
is everything we need to make our chocolate our
keto chocolate ice cream we have 390g of Cream,
I'm going to put all the cup measurements as
well on the screen and in the description so
you don't worry about that, 197g of water, in here
we have our 36g of inulin and our 2g of tara gum,
here we have our 25g of cocoa powder and finally
in here 107g of allulose. If you are using cups
be careful measuring the allulose, go too far
with it or you put in 20-30g too much and your
ice cream will not freeze it's really really
strong (it's affecting the freezing point) so
there we go I just want to say that the cocoa
powder is this which is "deZaan True Gold" it
is my new favorite cocoa powder for now, it
has an incredible taste very good texture not
affiliated just recommending it and I don't
know where you can get it over here I brought
it in from the UK or more importantly I had my
family bring it over to the UK when they came
last it's incredible stuff. I know you can get it
in the US, I don't think you can get it in Canada
hey use what you got... but this is better
;) shameless plug out the way, we're going
to prepare all this in a pan and let it cool
down quite simply put all your ingredients in
together make sure you stir your
stabilizer in with your allulose
and or your sugar like so you can add it all
in together it doesn't make any difference,
make a triumphant mess and in that goes stir
that in and we're going to wait for our our
mixture to come up a little bit in temperature
to around 50°C/122°F before we add our cocoa
powder finally stir in your cocoa powder making
sure your lumps are dissolved and it's completely
homogenized and bring your ice cream base
up to 80-85°C / 180°F and turn the heat off
before it gets too hot. And there we go, that
makes sure that your stabilizer is completely
hydrated and the ice cream will be a perfect
texture once it's churned. What we're going
to do now is pop this in a container and let
it cool down in the fridge. With the ice cream
base prepared and chilling in the fridge, the
last thing we need to do is make our caramel.
Now you need to be careful making caramel
with sugar substitutes because erythritol
will recrystallize almost every time it's just
an inherent part of the scientific or chemical
makeup of that sugar substitute so I do recommend
if you're going to do this get some alos it it's
perfect for creating sugar-free caramel if you
can't get alos you can use monk fruit sugar,
coconut sugar they also work but obviously coconut
sugar isn't a sugar free substitute per se,
it has quite a few carbs in it but I'm sure
you've got your favorite. I'm positive there
are some other brands out there sugar substitutes
just choose one that doesn't have erythritol in
it and you'll be fine. So let's get all our
ingredients prepared right here and here we
have our Allulose so we've got 80g worth of
Allulose and here we have 45g of whipping
cream/heavy whipping cream at room temperature
and we have 28g of butter at room temperature,
vanilla extract and a high quality salt. Don't use
standard table salt for this because it's a very
different puppy and just doesn't taste as nice so
with all that we're going to get this on the hob
and prepare our caramel to cool down at the same
time as the ice cream so for this Keto so no sugar
caramel you're going to start with your allulose
straight in the pan and you also going to add in
your butter at the same time and we are going to
wait for that to, help if I turned the hob on hey,
and we're going to wait for that to melt on its
own without touching it or stirring it like I'm
doing right now. When your butter and sugar start
to dissolve and come together you're going to
just swirl this around make sure everything is
completely dissolved together and we're going
to keep an eye on this pretty heartily cuz
we're going to take it off when it starts to
brown. It's starting to brown now which
means within the next minute or two we're
likely going to get to the color that we
want we just want a rich caramel color but
not too dark okay. So we're down to the
color that we want now a nice rich brown
we're going to turn the hob off because
we're going to add in our room temperature
cream. If it spits please be
careful and we're just going to stir this until
it starts to cool down there we go we're going
to leave this now to completely cool on a on a
unheated part of the hob before we pour it into
container so with our caramel cooled down
enough so there's no longer bubbling,
we're going to add in our vanilla. We don't need
a lot here so we're just going to use 1/4 to 1/2
teaspoon. Get that mixed in, look how gorgeous
this caramel looks, and finally we're just going
to add in a small pinch of salt we're not making
salted caramel we're using the salt to boost the
current flavors just like the vanilla is doing
so now that that's ready we're going to put that
in a container and get it in the fridge with
our ice cream base, completely chilled down.
Now we're going to take it out of the fridge
and just give it a quick stir we want to make
sure that there's no lumps, there's no surface
deformation or anything we're just going to give
this a nice stir to make sure that it's all
come together and then we're going to pour it
into our pre-chilled ice cream machine. I leave
mine running for 10 minutes prior to doing this
and at the same time we're going to bring
our caramel out the fridge it's a perfect
consistency as it is now so let's come back
in a minute once your ice cream is churned
to approximately this stage. Get all your
components ready to load up your tubs. So
what you're going to do is do one scoop of
your ice cream and one solid drizzle of your
luscious caramel and keep going until all your
containers are filled up and put them all in the
freezer.
Our keto chocolate caramel ice cream has been in
the freezer for a couple of days we're going to
get some scooped up and talk about the caramel and
really quite how good this ice cream turned out
As you can see the consistency texture
of the ice cream is perfect the caramel
is perfect this has been in
the fridge for 2 days and it
is beautiful, spoons no problem straight out
the fridge whatsoever. Now I wasn't going to
call this Rolo ice cream I don't know why because
if you don't have Rolos where you're from, they're
little chocolate (these are Rollo minis) little
chocolate cylinders with, over here, gooey caramel
In England the caramel was quite hard and in
the Colder Weather they were like eat bullets
but it's a milk chocolate this cocoa powder
is beautiful, I mean this I think is my new
favorite coca powder for the moment it's a
milky chocolate profile so if we're looking
at numbers it's somewhere around the 30-35%
cocoa solid kind of range so if you were to
go and buy chocolate with that kind of cocoa
solid range, that's the taste that you're
going to get from this. It works beautifully, it
dissolves really easily, which is something that
coca powder can struggle with but let's
see how good this one actually tastes.
The last keto.... quick mustache wipe .....the
last keto ice cream, the coffee chip the rebel
coffee chip copy that was amazing this is even
better. My wife and I tried this just a quick
spoonful last night and we are shocked at how
good this actually is for a zero sugar ice
cream. Obviously keto so it's ultra low carbs,
I'll put on the screen what the numbers actually
are but uh while we're here and I've got my phone
in front of me we are looking at 9.5 net carbs per
tub so that's you know 500 mL tub or one pint
which gives you a 4.5 net carb per serving per
half tub that's pretty pretty damn good uh and to
have it taste like this, you know what it's like,
you go to the store and you buy a keto ice
cream it's junk mostly the textures off it
just has this weird kind of aftertaste to it it's
not pleasant. This I would pay money that your
customers or your family or you would be able
to tell that this has zero sugar and ultra low
carbs it's creamy it has a nice strong chocolate
flavor but the way that the sugars work in this,
or the sugar substitutes work, in this it's not
super sweet it's kind of got the the taste of a
standard sugar based ice cream that's somewhere
in the 10 to 12% range so you get all those
flavors coming through. You get the flavor of
that caramel which tastes exactly like normal
sugar based caramel but it just uses allulose.
This is rapidly becoming one of my favorite
methods of making ice cream. If you like keto
ice cream, you like no sugar ice cream and you
want to know how to make it as good as everyone
else makes their sugar based, let me know in the
comments. I'll be doing more keto and no sugar
ice creams moving forward. I'm a big fan of these
so thanks for much for watching don't forget to
like and subscribe and I'll see you next week.